# **Todd Krieger**

Plymouth, Michigan | 616-566-9483 | toddcodesforfood@gmail.com <u>Github | LinkedIn | Blog</u>

### Software Engineer/Full Stack Developer

Fresh from a career of building things and solving problems at a tier 1 automotive supplier, I am now breaking into a new, rewarding career, solving harder problems and building more complex things in the world of software. To do this I apply years of experience with individual and team problem solving practices, along with many other transferable skills, to a fresh toolbox of web technologies.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

HTML, JavaScript, CSS, React, React Router, Ruby, Rails, Active Record, PostgreSQL, Git, GitHub, relational databases, Third party API integration.

#### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

# Buddy System - GitHub | Demo

App to help people with niche outdoor hobbies find and plan trips together, minimizing the risks of going alone.

- Utilized a Ruby on Rails backend leveraging authentication and authorization to keep user accounts private.
- Designed a PostgreSQL relational database allowing for flexible deployment options.
- Created a React frontend utilizing React Router and custom validation ensuring correct data is rendered.
- Integrated Google Maps JavaScript API for location data, and visualization, providing interactive maps.
- Product features include, user signup, full CRUD actions for trips, and message system for trip attendees.

## Game On! - GitHub Frontend | GitHub Backend | Demo

App that lets people connect with other people interested in team sports, to participate in, or host, pickup sports games.

- Implemented a React Javascript front end resulting in a responsive site for the user.
- Harnessed Ruby on Rails to create custom backend routes, delivering information to the client.
- Leveraged Bcrypt to provide secure password protection for users.
- Developed custom authentication and authorization to restrict data to the associated user.

# NASA Daily Content Display - GibHub | Demo

App fetches data/content from the NASA Daily Astronomy Photo API and displays it. Links provided for HD version.

- Leveraged vanilla HTML, CSS, and JavaScript to fetch and display content.
- Accepted user input to select dates from which to load content, drastically reducing initial load times.
- Listened for User input on thumbnails to select content for detailed display.
- Integrated iframes tags in order to display video content from external sources such as youtube.

## **EXPERIENCE**

**Application Engineer** Iliin USA

Novi, Michigan 09/2017 - 06/2020

- Collaborated with multiple internal and external customers to define metrics and requirements, expediting sales.
- Acted as the primary customer contact for all engineering related items, making sure customer deadlines were met.
- Perfected products by error proofing designs and production methods with engineering quality documentation.

## **Composite Materials Research Engineer**

Ann Arbor, Michigan 01/2021 - 07-2021

**Trimer Technologies** 

- Fabricated and tested composite material samples ascertaining mechanical property values.
- Contributed to project reports and official documents resulting in continued funding for projects.
- Automated rudimentary tasks with MatLab.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Flatiron School** 

Plymouth, Michigan

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

09/ 2021 - 01/2022

Michigan Technological University

Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering.

Houghton, Michigan 09/2017 - 07/2017